as you can see in the top I have I've
started a war I accidentally killed some
pillagers and now just the craziest
situation is happening the soldiers have
taken an absolute beating and these guys
just gave up they're just like nah I'm
happy to just chill it they're not
fussed they're not fussed at all they're
just
just chillin what is going on I think I
might just leave them here I mean look
at this oh just taking over our boat
right and then there's some sort of deal
going this is just madness sheer madness
so I'm just gonna give this I'm just
gonna give this pillager a little tour
so mister pillager this is our base if
you look over there there's a mine that
scar made over there there's the portal
that scar made over there there's a
snail that scar made you know maybe I
should make a few things around here as
well anyway hello my name is grant and
welcome back to another episode of
haunted craft you know this is um I'd
like to say that this is normal but this
is actually really really normal I think
Wigan I think we're gonna have to get
rid of these guys oh I'm sorry that was
mean of me I showed you the world and
then I and then I removed you from it oh
wait no the raids not over great there's
loads of like I have been steadily the
reason that I have 18 deaths is because
the iron golem situation here is crazy
like they just keep spawning and these
guys are well they're in a they're in a
right state new please give us bread we
need more bread basically I don't have
to do anything these golems should take
care of everything for me oh well isn't
there's a lot of them this time
flying everywhere and to think I was
trying to get rid of these iron golems
where's the bread where's the bread me
it me and the boys just waiting for the
raid oof you look like you've been
better yeah they come golems go-go-go my
minions go no no ok ok ok my bad my bad
my bad
oh no that's the iron golems are losing
yeah well I'm just stay out of this one
if I can
where are my trousers I'm okay my face
isn't okay though I just want my
trousers back oh please okay they at
least they can't get into the villages
all right this is gonna be tough but we
got this we need to get that guy there
the one with the flag here we go this is
a montage of me becoming a warrior right
your app yes these are the worst of they
ride ravages now when was that a thing
and they're destroying my jungle we're
just gonna play it safe I think it might
take a while but we'll get there yes yes
all right I got a better idea
come on fellas come on come on follow me
follow me there we go okay okay okay I'm
leaving I'm leaving I'm out here looking
for lover and what do I find what a
pesky bird oh you look just like
Professor beak goodbye my dudes and
goodbye the raid in the top of the
screen wow he's not going out without
fight there we go raid complete
[Music]
we got the achievement here scoffs Kyle
gets here of the village oh yeah they're
giving me they're giving me the best
deals the best deals thanks with a word
they're all threads definitely thanks
thanks for Dell breathe
thank you for that okay well that was a
bit of an odd start to the episode but
let's crack on with what I actually
wanted to do I've got quite the
collection of Minecraft heads going on
here and I also saw I've had a message
from mumbo but I haven't actually had a
look inside yet Oh a diamond
I got good Lowell well is it as simple
as that
hold on if he can just say I got good
law and that's it I don't know I I still
don't know what that means I am looking
forward to finding out but I can take
the 18 jungle doors from his Mordor
thing and I can say I got doors Lowell
and I'm for all the jungle doors here I
got doors he knows what I'm up to so
just proved it oh I just let him know
that I'm still doing my job
taking the doors of my fellow Hermits I
wonder how long it's gonna be before
everyone just starts hiding their doors
from me so even though that wasn't the
start that I wanted to have it's the
start that we had and think that's
actually worked out really well I got
loads of resources I've got some trading
with the villages I got hero at the
village and they cleared out all of
those pesky iron golems that would not
go they'd have killed me 20 times now
pretty much but what I did want to do in
this episode is actually get started on
the mega base obviously I'm not going to
be able to build the whole thing but I
was hoping we can maybe get a platform
done and lay down the basic foundation
and try and get the whole shape
organized so let's hop into a little
time lapse and start building this thing
it's gonna be absolutely mediocre for
now because it's not gonna be done let's
go
[Music]
I've kind of stopped the time-lapse a
little bit early just because I realized
a one or two things one I realized that
this platform was not nearly big enough
and I'm quickly running out of stone so
you could see I've got some baubles that
I've added on but that means it won't
fit and secondly I'm not actually sure I
want to commit to this particular
foundation layout however really like
where this is going it really looks epic
especially if you're down here you know
this manner is really going to lord it
over it's gonna be enormous over this
thing and look at the size of this
platform
hopefully just by looking at this thing
you can really get an idea for what I'm
going for and the angles are the big
thing diagonal building I'm really
committing to some difficult details
later on and I mean this is just the
base layer at the moment this is gonna
get probably way more complicated what
scars fighting scar is fighting the with
uh some on the wither nice oh yeah there
it is yeah good luck scar I wish you
well some of us some of us aren't there
yet however that is a really good point
I could definitely use a beacon right
right about now because with
terraforming you know you want that
instant mine so for now I think I'm
gonna have to leave this or maybe
off-camera
I'm going to fill in all of the rest of
this platform really try and nail down
exactly what this foundation is gonna
look like cuz at the moment I don't feel
it's wide enough in certain places maybe
Oh scar no it's gone oh is he okay
this is why you never throw away extra
stone you will need it for projects like
this I'm gonna just check oh I'm going
back in good luck scar we salute you you
know what one of the best things about
being next to scar this season is
hopefully he'll be able to help me a
little bit with the terraforming of this
creating some really nice got very
distinct
style and his terraforming skills are
way better than mine so I'm hoping that
he can help me I could terraform pretty
well but skull has this amazing ability
to just put the final touches to make it
seem really really nice I mean it's like
a skull that's not even the wither made
that's not even the wither you're
fighting the wither and you died by the
zombies hand okay
that's the that's the third death now by
the wither
the Sun is setting on scars life he's
good he's definitely gonna lose his
stuff I mean chuckles I'm in danger
I'm covered scar I'm coming I'm coming
for his buddy I'm good boy don't worry
I'm on the case
I want the case buddy well we got what
we got let's get my diamonds oh man this
isn't gonna be good this is not gonna be
good don't worry buddy
I'm coming I'm in the mind okay I know
where he is I'll only need my sword for
this
grreat to the rescue okay for you he
said he's an okay please God don't worry
we go in here we go Korea to the rescue
Wow my legs look so enormous oh yeah
where is he where is he in the mind in
the mind in the mind where's this wither
at where's this with it oh man it's full
health dude I got this don't you worry
T&T man is on the case oh all right
you know you know that's cool do you not
fear
[Music]
this for my name is the g-man I didn't
bring a pic i you know g-man doesn't
g-men doesn't need pics you know G man's
got TNT jiva and just G man goes in oh
[Applause]
that's definitely all my stuff does
anyone else need saving hero services a
g-man to the risky I think that went
about as badly as it possibly could have
gone oh man oh man I've probably lost
all my gear thank goodness I got rid of
everything else
oh we going okay we Scout G man's coming
don't worry
round two here we go oh my goodness I'm
so sorry scar respawn point set don't
worry I got this I got a spare sword I'm
scared I'm still in danger
yeah buddy I'm still in danger too and
you know you know what else you know
what else car my TT didn't even damage
him I think I lost all my stuff yeah
oh no stuck in here
I lost my light trip ska this is the
worst design I've ever seen for a bet
Scott Scott this is bad design for a
[\h__\h] you're telling me you own telling
me move that other way story I'm going
in ska
round three here we go oh man does he
heal does the wither heals
oh man the wither heels I don't know if
I can save us here oh no I think I think
gee man super power is losing all his
stuff
I lost everything good job I took the
only the weapons I needed so I only lost
my armor and a light sherbert oh boy oh
boy this is gonna be a rough journey
you are kidding why is my portal up here
all right we need emergency XP this is
the equivalent of going into my weapons
vault now right 46 levels smashing okay
I think we're gonna have to choose this
from a distance using a bow don't know
how well this is gonna go fast
enchantments not too bad we have to
choose this the old-fashioned way I
don't know why I thought any of this was
gonna work okay this time g-man doesn't
fight with his sword g-man fights with
his brain but also his sword
Scott he's kitted out we got another
hero come on come on go go go go go go
go this time we fight him using a
superpower to brain cells he has one
brain cell all right we take this the
smart way this time and please I don't
want to lose my silk scribe respawn set
Scott you're literally the worst you are
my only hope
okay Jim as not scared
let's get let's go I need torches my
only weakness darkness the plan is to
cheese boom out of the way
dip in would she we go back we dip in we
shoot we go back we dip in we shoot and
we go back no no no come on Scott we can
do this g-man got you yet what who else
needs saving
I lost everything like the Cavalry's
here
oh oh thanks for thanks for showing up
when you did tango I figured out what my
superpower is what losing all my stuff
did you get the star by chance I did
thank the hermit's in the skies oh it's
just some reason I thought I could I
could come in here I'm so sorry I
thought I could come in here blow the
weather up and that would be it
little did I know the weather ignites
the TNT
my bad ma you know I'm standing there
and I was thinking you were you were in
cahoots for a moment with me whither I
assume you using this for biggity beacon
yes yes I think that's when I was here
for I honestly I was hit in the head so
many times a little bit taste I am sorry
about the bed incident I
that was a poor placement on my yeah it
turns out you need you need two brain
cells to kill the wither not not one and
that bed placement was one brain cell
placement we combined we combined the
power of the g-man yeah you know the one
brain cell together you know we did too
it was three brain cells and that's what
did it that's what so we literally just
finished fighting that wither and scar
has kindly offered me in a mess
she said that he is willing to give me
hit one of his spare alight reparent
he's got quite a few and I'm I'm
actually gonna take him up on that
because there's no way I'm going to the
end and doing that all over again
so yeah I did kind of come and help
Skaar out so I'm gonna take him up on
that Elijah offer thank you dude thank
you I I know I helped you out there but
I really didn't want to lose my Electra
I'm so sorry about the Electra I'm sorry
for blowing you up I'm still withered if
you don't notice I'm still emitting
particles ie I think it's affected your
one brain cell dude I didn't see
anything all right
so like I said thank you so much for
helping me oh oh no that was
anti-climatic I'm gonna put it up here
like it's just great trade off it gives
you more breathing ability underwater
that's manageable you don't want to give
me the you don't wanna give me the
nether star instead I could really use a
beacon you know what we could we could
share how about we share we are close
enough to be able to share beacon that
would be look at a glow that was harder
and that was what are you gonna make
with anyway oh my gosh dude I've been
trying to make a creeper farm for a week
police say rockets please say rockets
okay I've got a sugarcane farm if if you
want to go halfsies I will help you make
the creeper farm and then we can have
Rockets for days aha rockets for days so
yeah well I've been collecting stuff for
the beacons but I've got like almost
yeah I actually have two stacks of iron
so we just need a little bit more maybe
we could find the gold yeah yeah we'll
make an ugly beacon and yeah you know
what let's just make it now I'm up for
it okay so let's uh we got our Electra
back thank goodness and actually this
sounds like a fantastic plan what we're
gonna do is we're gonna we're gonna work
with Skaar and we're gonna between the
two of us hopefully get enough rockets
you know I've got the sugarcane he's got
plans for a creeper farm if we help each
other out scratch each other's back we
could have we could have so many rockets
and probably even make our first shop
that would be awesome
alright let's let's get on and make this
I don't know where's plans are but I'm
sure
figure it out let's err that's
time-lapse this and get it going
[Music]
Wow what a project that was a seriously
long night that scar and I spent
building this thing hours and hours and
it is I am very very happy to say
working it's not particularly handsome
at the moment it is just a hole in the
ground but you know between scar and I
we you know we know how to build we
could make this look really really nice
sometime in the future I think we're
pretty sick of it to be honest at the
moment but now he's a really good time
to top up on my gunpowder because I'm
actually running pretty low on rockets
so we've done a kill the chamber made of
magma block it's not the most efficient
but we wanted to keep this whole thing
underground and look at that it is
already producing a really decent amount
of gunpowder that is excellent this
should keep me topped up for a very long
time and since we finished that I have
actually been finalizing some of the
foundation levels of my base and I am
also very pleased to say it's done it is
well I'm well I'm pretty sure it's done
there's probably gonna be some little
details that get added on the side but
on the whole I'm pretty happy with how
this looks but I noticed something and
the second that I noticed it I can't
unnotice it it looks like a space
invader like an actual space look all I
gotta do is add a couple of eyes and
check it out
okay maybe maybe the space invaders look
a little Lester P than that oh man but
you could go in to see it it is meant to
be a foundation level for a house but it
definitely looks like some sort of cute
machine at the moment so I'm gonna
continue working on this trying to get
every element of this just right and I
think that is going to be it for today's
episode it has been extremely extremely
busy we've done quite a lot we've got
the creeper farm going and we've started
our main base but most importantly we
saved scar from impending doom so I will
see you in the next episode good